<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<root>
    <date date="1858-08-26">August 26.</date>

    <message num="1">
        <heading from="Newfoundland" to="Valentia">Newfoundland to Valentia.</heading>
        <text>“Why don’t you give ‘finis’<info>(signal)</info> when you have done?”</text>
    </message>

    <message num="2">
        <heading from="Valentina" to="Newfoundland">Valentia to Newfoundland.</heading>
        <text>“We have had storm, with thunder. Cable put to earth for one hour twenty-five
            minutes.” <info>(Professor Thomson was testing from <time>9 A.M.</time> till <time>11.30
                    A.M.</time> On the morning of <date date="1858-08-26">Thursday, August 26</date>, there was a
                storm of heavy rain, accompanied by thunder and lightning, in Newfoundland. It
                commenced at <time>2.30 A. M.</time>, and at<time> 3.05 A.M.</time> the lightning
                was so intense that the end of the cable was put to earth for protection. At
                    <time>4.30 A.M.</time> the storm ceased, and at <time>7.15 A. M.</time> the
                weather is noted as having been since very fine.)</info> “Can’t read your signals.
            Send slower, and repeat all.” “Your signals too weak to read.” “Your signals very weak.
            Have twenty messages for you. Will you take them?” “Your signals better. Repeat.”</text>
    </message>

    <message num="3">
        <heading from="Valentina" to="Newfoundland">Valentia to Newfoundland.</heading>
        <text>“Try only one galvanometer in circuit. We must understand stoppage of Monday night and
            learn how to manage.”</text>
    </message>
    <message num="4">
        <heading from="Newfoundland" to="Valentia">Newfoundland to Valentia.</heading>
        <text>“What do you mean by stoppage of Monday night?” “Understand. Go on.”</text>
    </message>
    <message num="5">
        <heading from="Valentina" to="Newfoundland">Valentia to Newfoundland.</heading>
        <text>“Saward to De Sauty:—T. H. Brooking &amp; Co. authorize an advance on your order by
            Hepburn to extent of one hundred pounds.” “Thomson to De Sauty:—Your signals were very
            weak Monday night at <time>1.12</time> Greenwich time. None came from<time> 2.44</time>
            to <time>4.06.</time> Then very weak indeed. Improved later. At <time>8</time> good. We
            sent one message eight times, from <time>2.45</time> till <time>5.12</time>. Had no
            reply. Stoppage again from <time>2 </time>to <time>6</time> in the afternoon. Can you
            explain why? Tell us each time.”</text>
    </message>
    <message num="6">
        <heading from="Newfoundland" to="Valentia">Newfoundland to Valentia.</heading>
        <meassage>“Understand. New York, <date>25 August</date>. Samuel Gurney, Esq., London:—Many
            thanks for message received. Americans wild with joy. Great celebration throughout the
            land, <date date="1858-09-01">September 1</date> and <date date="1858-09-02">2</date>. “C.W. FIELD.”</meassage>
    </message>
</root>
